Guide to the Strong family papers, 1870-1977
Strong family papers, 1870-1977
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Strong family papers, 1870-1977.
3933
Strong family.
1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, a scrapbook, photographs, genealogies, and other material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes correspondence of and biographical material concerning Frank Strong; diaries, transcript of diaries, and a scrapbook kept by his mother, Mary Foote Strong, 1902-1918; photograph album of Frank Strong's daughter, Evelyn Strong Claassen; genealogies of Frank Strong's family and of his wife, Mary Evelyn Ranson. Also, printed material concerning the University of Kansas Chancellors; photographs of John Butler Strong, Mary Foote Strong and her two sons, Frank and Otis.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Frank Strong, originally from Cayuga County, New York, was chancellor of the University of Kansas, 1902-1920.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes correspondence of and biographical material concerning Frank Strong; diaries, transcript of diaries, and a scrapbook kept by his mother, Mary Foote Strong, 1902-1918; photograph album of Frank Strong's daughter, Evelyn Strong Claassen; genealogies of Frank Strong's family and of his wife, Mary Evelyn Ranson. Also, printed material concerning the University of Kansas Chancellors; photographs of John Butler Strong, Mary Foote Strong and her two sons, Frank and Otis.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Strong family.; Claasen, Evelyn Strong.; Strong, Frank, 1859-1934.; Strong, Frank.; Strong, John Butler.; Strong, Mary Evelyn Ranson, 1870-1953.; Strong, Mary Foote.; Strong, Otis.; University of Kansas.
Places:
Cayuga County (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Professional Correspondence of Frank Strong. All copies and typescripts. 1895-1903, 1913-1940, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Diaries and Notes of Mary Foote Strong. Diaries, 1871, 1876, 1890, 1902-1918. Dates of Notes, 1773, 1776, 1859, 1863, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- The Genealogical Family Record of Frank Strong. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Genealogical Family Record of Mary Evelyn Ransom (Mrs. Frank Strong). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Personal Correspondence of Frank Strong and his Family, 1835, 1863-1864, 1874, 1881-1882, 1889-1908, 1914-1935. All typescript copies and photocopies. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "A Biography of my Grandfather, Frank Strong," by Sarah Claassen Severinghaus, 1977. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Printed Articles on University of Kansas Chancellors, 1962, 1966. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence re: Frank Strong's investments, 1902-1954. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Personal correspondence of Frank Strong, his Family, and others, 1890-1946. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Album of Frank Strong's Family, Volume I, 1776-1902. Folders: Part I and Part II. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Album of Frank Strong's Family, Volume II, 1902-1963. Folders: Part I and Part II. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- High school classbooks and college magazines, 1880, 1889, 1919, 1934. 5 publications. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- One Volume of the Inauguration of Ernest Hiram Lindsley at University of Kansas. The volume also contains the Inaugural Address by Frank Strong, Page 5. (Administrations of the University of Kansas, 1866-1920 ). (Box 1, Folder 13)
- One special sourvenir historical issue of the Oregon Emerald (University of Oregon, Eugene, Oregon). "The University of Oregon's First 100 Years," Vol. 74, No. 65, Oct. 31, 1972. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Two reprints from the American Historical Review. "The Causes of Cromwell's West Indian Expedition," Vol. IV, No. 2, Jan. 1899, by Frank Strong, and, "A Forgotten Danger to the New England Colonies," 1899, by Frank Strong. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- One Family Scrapbook kept by Mary Foote Strong. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Three Certificates:
  - U.S. Treasury Dept. Office of Internal Revenue to John Butler Strong dated Aug. 1, 1879. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Women's Baptist Home Mission Society Life Membership to Mary Foote Strong dated July 18, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ulysses S. Grant appointment of John B. Strong as Collector for the Internal Revenue Service, 24th District, Auburn, N.Y. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Eight Decorative Convention and Award Ribbons in a 6x9 white envelope. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 9 1/2" x 15" white envelope of newspaper clippings all copied on permalife. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Photographs (in 7 1/4" x 5 1/4" white folder):
  - John Butler Strong as a young man, ca. 1851. Daguerreotype. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Mary Foote Strong as a young woman, ca. 1850s. Daguerreotype. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Mary Foote Strong with her two sons, Frank and Otis Strong, 1870s. (Box 1, Folder 22)